Vaggelis Michos | CV



Vaggelis Michos

Software Engineer / Scientific Researcher on Digital Telecommunications

- emichos@ceid.upatras.gr
- 69934114523
- ru6.cti.gr/ru6/users/evangelos-michos
- vagg777
- vagg777

Languages

- Greek (Native)
- English (Professional)
- French (Professional)

Interests

- Resource Management in Mobile Telecommunication Systems
- Design and Optimisation of Wireless Networks
- Fifth Generation of Mobile Networks (5G)
- Software Development

About (Download CV as PDF)

Evangelos Michos was born in 1995 in Athens, Greece. He entered the Department of Information and Communication System Engineering at University of Patras in 2013 and attained his degree in 2019. He has obtained the Michigan Certificate of Proficiency in English and the Diplome D' Etudes en Langue Francaise B2. He joined Research Unit 6 in 2018 and his interests involve web development and next generation mobile telecommunications networks.

Education

Diploma Degree in Computer Engineering

September 2013 - July 2019

Department of Computer Engineering and Informatics, University of Patras

Postgraduate Computer Engineering Student from the Department of Computer Engineering & Informatics, University of Patras.

- Diploma's Degree: 7.41
- Integrated Master's Degree

Online Course 'Introduction to Python'

February 2019 - March 2019

Online Course Center of Mathesis, Institute of Technology and Research

The online course - duration of 6 weeks - with an estimated work of 60 hours was provided through the OpenEdX/gr platform of Mathesis, in line with all already established techniques and eduational specifications.

Lab Assistant for the 'Databases Laboratory' course

September 2017 - February 2018

Department of Computer Engineering and Informatics, University of Patras

Survaillance of undergraduate students during the execution of the laboratory exercises, as long as providence of technical and consultant support.

Educational Programming on Scratch Language

October 2015 - November 2015

Hellenic Open University, Patras

The programme - duration of 25 hours - was conducted using mixed education, combining face-to-face educational meetings as well as asynchronous teleconferencing

Experiences

Software Engineer

July 2018 - Present

Distributed Systems & Telematics Lab, University of Patras

Participation in the European project "Sustainable Tourism Strategies for the Conservation and Utilization of the Mediterranean Coastal and Marine Natural Heritage (INHERIT)" of the Interreg MED Program. Period: 20/07/2018 - 28/02/2019 and 01/04/2019 - 31/12/2019. Roles:

- Development of Communication & Dissemination plan
- Gathering relevant material for website / updates / brochures / posters / library interviews & videos / email campaigns
- Collection of relevant material for sending newsletters
- Gathering relevant material for organizing relevant information meetings
- Preparing material for tourism approach final conference / press releases and kits / meetings with media representatives / media appearances / horizontal project events

- Participate in the development of a coordination plan including guidelines and forms to be used by all partners to monitor the achievement of results and to ensure the effective implementation of deliverables.
- Providing input to the methodology being developed

Scientific Researcher

March 2018 - Present

Distributed Systems & Telematics Lab, University of Patras

Scientific research on mobile networks and applications that propose innovative techniques to meet the high performance requirements of Next Generation Networks, as well as research on the latest developments in wired networks, including design, implementation, simulation and testing of existing networks technologies.

Participate in the development of a web-based tool that enables tourism SMEs to self-assess and improve their water management and conservation business, and public authorities to view statistics on their current status sustainability of water management by tourism SMEs in their area. The tool can be found here.

- Participate in the planning of the questionnaire that the tool offers to SME users
- Participate in the development of a questionnaire evaluation system, incorporating user performance rating mechanisms, as well as mechanisms that provide recommendations on how to improve performance
- Contribute to the development of tabs in the tool, which provides access to basic metrics and data visualizations
- Ongoing maintenance, updating and management of the online tool and database

Software Engineering Intern

July 2014 - August 2014

Ergologic AEBE, Patras

My role during my internship was application programming using JAVA programming language.

Projects

Previous/Active Participation in the following projects:

CASTWATER - Castwater is the first Interreg MED project to support sustainable tourism policies & practices on water efficiency in coastal areas. The transnational challenge is to reduce the impact of tourism activities on environmental heritage.

GPP4GROWTH - GPP4Growth brings together nine partners from nine countries, to exchange experiences & practices and improve their capacities on implementing resource efficiency policies that promote eco-innovation and green growth through Green Public Procurement (GPP).

INHERIT - Sustainable Tourism Strategies to conserve and valorise the Mediterranean coastal and maritime natural heritage.

GUIDEME - GuideMe is a platform that provides guidance and security for these people when moving outside their homes.

Scientific Publications

Resource-Efficient Decoupling in Ultra Dense 5G Networks

C. Bouras, V. Kokkinos and E. Michos

International Symposium on Networks, Computers and Communications (ISNCC), 2019

Efficient 5G Network Decoupling using dynamic Modulation and Coding Scheme Selection

C. Bouras, V. Kokkinos and E. Michos

International Conference on Broad-Band Wireless Computing, Communication and Applications (BWCCA), 2019

Programming Skills

Java

HTML5 & CSS

Matlab

Scratch

 \mathbf{SQL}

 \mathbf{C}

Python

Javascript/JQuery

PHP

Kibana/Elasticsearch